James Names Moffet

James Moffet

335A Harvard St. #10 Cambridge, MA, USA +1.773.354.1500 jim@jamesdavidmoffet.com

Design Researcher

jamesdavidmoffet.comjim@jamesdavidmoffet.comjamesdavidmoffet

Code for America

155 9th Street
San Francisco, CA, USA

Dear CfA,

I am currently seeking collaborators for my thesis research at the Graduate School of Design at Harvard University. Cfa has been a guiding star in my intellectual and activist sky for many years and I'm to write to you today.

My thesis research concerns issues of civic technology, usercentered and co-design for public good, and the building and maintenance of community in an over-connected and undercommitted world.

My background is in data systems design for the labor movement, with several years of field organizing for political campaigns before that. Ultimately, trying to get closer to the grassroots led me to user-centered design and all of the thorny issues of communities, tech and power that lie behind it.

I would like to discuss any opportunities you might have to work toward these goals over the coming year. I'm a deft hand at several flavors of design research, as well as data analysis (including ML), interface design, software and hardware engineering.

I believe that your mission aligns squarely with my passions and expertise and I would look forward to the opportunity to illuminate meaningful problems and design some considered solutions with you.

Sincerely,

James Moffet



Design Researcher

jamesdavidmoffet.com

jim@jamesdavidmoffet.com

in jamesdavidmoffet

about

As a designer and technologist, I am obsessed with discovering how technology may be deployed to deliver an alternative future. As a graduate design researcher, I have learned to temper this obsession through a range of ethnographic research techniques and critical theory that have taught me to resist the internal inertia technologies tend to assert and instead apply user-centered, systems-level thinking to the awesome challenge of improving people's lives.

education

2016 - 2018

Harvard University Graduate School of Design

Master's degree, Design Technology Studies

SKIIS

Design Research
UI/UX Design
Data Science
Software Engineering
Hardware Engineering
Public Speaking
Project Management
Product Design

work experience

OutVote/COMM!T

2017 Cambridge, MA, USA Founder / UXR / Data Scientist
 Founded civic tech startup COMM!T to test efficacy of peer-enforced smart contracts in driving civic participation.
 Joined forces OutVote civic networking startup in running 2017 election MVPs.

Civic Tech Fellow

Summer 2017 Cambridge, MA, USA UXR / Designer / Engineer
 Developed civic technology for the City of Cambridge with a focus on open source citizen analytics apps that can be deployed by volunteer organizations with minimal technical volunteer labor.

MIT Community Innovators Lab

2016 - 2017 Cambridge, MA, USA Project Lead / UXR / Engineer
 Managed a democratic capacity
 mapping project for the MIT Community
 Innovators lab. Oversaw research labor
 as well as designed and engineered a
 democratic capacity mapping and organizational partnership tool.

Fulbright Research Fellow

2015 - 2016 Cambridge, MA, USA Design Research / Project Mgmt
Researched community fablabs at the
Center for Media, Data and Society at
CEU in Budapest. Also piloted OpenLab
public design workshops in UXR,
interface design and hardware/software
prototyping for public projects.

SEIU

2009 - 2014 Portland, OR, USA

Data Architect

Full-cycle design and development of a financial-member system handling 25M records, 50 corp. partners, \$5M revenue.